[{"id": "5fe8f91d01dd7bf43be5e84b", "question": "A shaving commercial featuring which two famous people launched the whole Super Bowl commercial phenomenon?", "answer": "Farah Fawcett and Joe Namath", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba2d8874c93a3298b2136", "question": "Which Italian won the 1998 Tour de France bicycle race?", "answer": "Marco Pantani", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f5666033a95c66dc4fe762", "question": "What is the capital of Michigan?", "answer": "Lansing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933b", "question": "On the TV show \"South Park\", which character wears a blue hat with a red pom-pom on it?", "answer": "Stan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f3eeaaf848b908361b86a", "question": "What country's flag features a trident?", "answer": "Barbados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad08", "question": "What H-word means designing, displaying and describing coats of arms and badges?", "answer": "Heraldry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde5141c6c6b019850c9a8e", "question": "In the Bible, who was Jacob's daughter?", "answer": "Dinah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7a", "question": "During what war was the novel \"M*A*S*H\" set?", "answer": "Korean War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51274ff04d658268c92d0", "question": "What was the most popular drink in colonial America?", "answer": "Nearly everyone in colonial America drank\u00a0tea, which explains the uproar when the British levied a tax on their favorite drink.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e539fe83fe1f2a824bba", "question": "Which god is considered the \"destroyer\" and is part of the Hindu Trinity?", "answer": "Shiva", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b775", "question": "What is a brigand?", "answer": "An armed bandit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8c", "question": "What was the primary source of food for the Comanche Indians?", "answer": "American bison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e13806d333868d34d725", "question": "Which African nation successfully resisted colonialism in the late 19th century?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdfbfbd003d27d341092bd8", "question": "How much lower does the Dead Sea get every year?", "answer": "One meter", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c993fbde8045e48466ef", "question": "What is a group of jelly fish called?", "answer": "A smack", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f6", "question": "What is the lowest land point on Earth?", "answer": "Dead Sea shore, Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd6", "question": "What TV show did \"Diagnosis Murder\" spin off from?", "answer": "Jake and the Fatman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c2", "question": "What is the world's fastest growing plant?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0a", "question": "What author created the character of The Continental Op?", "answer": "Dashiell Hammett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f5a4ff048f679a45aad7", "question": "Which of your organs can regenerate itself up to 60%?", "answer": "Liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c35f7815febcc896f9262", "question": "What firm made the B25 Micro Computer?", "answer": "Burroughs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c347", "question": "What is the name of the test to determine whether a computer could convincingly imitate a human?", "answer": "The Turing test", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c774", "question": "What animal species name is slang for the mechanics profession?", "answer": "Monkeys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6f", "question": "What Nirvana and Smashing Pumpkins record produced later became the drummer in Garbage?", "answer": "Butch Vig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4543ff048f679a45ab92", "question": "What type of fish is a dangerous delicacy for sushi eaters if not correctly prepared?", "answer": "Blowfish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b6a901dd7bf43be5e7e0", "question": "Who coined the phrase \"slam dunk\"?", "answer": "Chick Hearn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad1b", "question": "\"Remember the Maine!\" was the rallying cry for what war?", "answer": "The Spanish-American War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c208", "question": "What year was the UK an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1908", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cd86877e98cb97778a38", "question": "Which US state hosts the world lumberjack championship?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c9640775fa611bce67eb", "question": "What is the name of an architectural certification in green design?", "answer": "LEED certification -- It is a verification that the design is resource-efficient, high-performing, healthy, and cost-effective.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce9", "question": "Tuesday Weld played Thalia Menninger on what TV show?", "answer": "The Many Loves of Dobie Gillis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636b0e967692ea851899a2", "question": "Which \"Committee of Five\" member was the only one to sign all four of the US state papers?", "answer": "Roger Sherman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab4e", "question": "What modern day country is the Lighthouse of Alexandria located in?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b3", "question": "\"He's In Town\" was a hit in 1964 for which British group?", "answer": "The Rockin' Berries", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caab", "question": "The cecum is part of which intestine?", "answer": "Large intestine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3e", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"The River Bank\"?", "answer": "The Wind in the Willows", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc6", "question": "What was the ultimate destination for most travelers of the Underground Railroad?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a7", "question": "In which European city did composer Richard Wagner die in 1883?", "answer": "Venice", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a7f", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Dragon Seed\"?", "answer": "Pearl S. Buck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d7a02596a59cbdfbd3b8", "question": "Martha Jane Canary was a sharpshooting frontierswoman better known as?", "answer": "Calamity Jane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ca", "question": "The TV show \"Frasier\" ran for how many seasons?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4a4349076251badbeab2", "question": "What holiday commemorates the day the last slaves were freed in Texas?", "answer": "Juneteenth -- It commemorates the day (June 19, 1865) that slaves in Galveston, Texas learned that they were free.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8b44ec223966ae8f8839", "question": "Which cast member of \"The Big Bang Theory\" has a real PhD?", "answer": "Mayim Bialik", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ad", "question": "Construction of the Colosseum began under the ruling of which emperor?", "answer": "Vespasian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe904c801dd7bf43be5e877", "question": "The Miami Marlins' baseball stadium is built on the former site of what other stadium?", "answer": "The Orange Bowl Stadium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70b", "question": "Which three states share a border with California?", "answer": "Arizona, Nevada and Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398fa", "question": "In what 1996 movie did Henry Winkler play the principal of Woodsboro High School?", "answer": "Scream", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996e", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Principal Skinner's mother?", "answer": "Agnes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f4c6ff048f679a45aacb", "question": "Lockiophobia is fear of what?", "answer": "Childbirth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b8", "question": "What unusual ingredient is often included in a Gibson cocktail?", "answer": "Pickled onion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd6", "question": "In 2001, David McCullough published a biography of which US Founding Father president?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0fb", "question": "Marvin Lee Aday is the real name of which well known singer?", "answer": "Meatloaf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946b", "question": "What movie earned Katharine Hepburn her last Oscar?", "answer": "On Golden Pond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef0", "question": "According to Modest Mouse, \"even if things get too heavy, what will we all do\"?", "answer": "Float On", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c6", "question": "How is rockstar Vincent Furnier better known?", "answer": "Alice Cooper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51195ff04d658268c92c7", "question": "Who was the first Republican Vice President of the United States?", "answer": "Hannibal Hamlin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf19", "question": "An onomastician studies what?", "answer": "Names", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb64", "question": "What rank in the US Army is just above the rank of First Lieutenant?", "answer": "Captain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b9", "question": "The nest of an eagle or bird of prey is called a what?", "answer": "Eyrie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b8ce8d94b094db915830a8", "question": "What did the letters \u201cC\u201d and \u201cN\u201d originally stand for in Toronto\u2019s CN Tower", "answer": "Canadian National", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339682", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of the frozen drink sold at the Kwik-E-Mart?", "answer": "Squishee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d9582596a59cbdfbd3c3", "question": "What items did the Stamp Act levy a tax on?", "answer": "Paper products", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25f", "question": "What is a somnambulist?", "answer": "A sleepwalker", "category": "science"}, {"id": "596dfb90cf3977a46e7ce44a", "question": "The average person has over 1,460 of what each year?", "answer": "Dreams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339566", "question": "Who directed, The Christmas Kid\"?", "answer": "Sid PInk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe9", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Prisoner of Zenda\"?", "answer": "Anthony Hope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f9", "question": "Over what ocean did Amelia Earhart disappear?", "answer": "The Pacific", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904987acf93664eb1048687", "question": "What is the name of the base twenty numbering system?", "answer": "Vigesimal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9dd", "question": "Which US state is the Evergreen State?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b3b5e662d71a53650fe2", "question": "Which famous composer produced his first operas at age 12?", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071c853745b36be73039cc", "question": "What is the name of the first space launch facility?", "answer": "Baikonur Cosmodrome", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae72", "question": "What berries did pregnant women of the Middle Ages avoid for fear their children would be born with birthmarks?", "answer": "Strawberries", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6ab5020565ad31a57c828", "question": "Who said, \"Pleasure is the bait of sin\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b955", "question": "What nickname was given to mafia boss Charlie Luciano?", "answer": "\"Lucky\" Luciano", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59e", "question": "How many tiles are there in a standard Scrabble game?", "answer": "100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d2", "question": "Who was the male star of the 1987 film \"Fatal Attraction\"?", "answer": "Michael Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9e", "question": "What movie did the villain Regina Giddens appear in?", "answer": "The Little Foxes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f4", "question": "What was the first planet to be discovered with a telescope?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c8", "question": "Who is credited with the discovery of penicillin?", "answer": "Alexander Fleming", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339448", "question": "Who directed the 1941 movie \"The Lady Eve\"?", "answer": "Preston Sturges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede4316ce05a3942286dd9", "question": "Parts of the movie \"Lara Croft: Tomb Raider\" were shot in what African country?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fc", "question": "What part of a sailor's uniform can be used in an emergency as a flotation device?", "answer": "The pants (also the hat)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7ddbff048f679a45ac00", "question": "Anthropophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "People or society", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92b", "question": "What article of attire is known as a \"corset\" around police precincts?", "answer": "Bulletproof Vest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fae", "question": "Who composed the music for the opera \"The Tales of Hoffman\"?", "answer": "Jacques Offenbach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef96c96ce05a3942286ea1", "question": "Which martial art does Miss Piggy practice?", "answer": "Karate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2c", "question": "In what sport are the Beaters in charge of batting away the Bludgers?", "answer": "Quidditch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a092", "question": "Who sang \"That's Alright Mama\"?", "answer": "Elvis Presley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339522", "question": "What silent film has been called the granddaddy of all Dracula movies?", "answer": "Nosferatu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1e", "question": "Which rabbit was the hero of some of Beatrix Potters stories?", "answer": "Peter Rabbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b01f", "question": "What was the last name of husband and wife Julius and Ethel, executed for treason in 1953?", "answer": "Rosenberg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f2", "question": "What is halite more commonly called?", "answer": "Rock salt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e67bfe83fe1f2a824bcd", "question": "What, in the 16th and 17th centuries, was a \"drunkard\u2019s cloak\"?", "answer": "It was a form of humiliation used to address people who were perceived as abusers of alcohol.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636d8d967692ea851899ad", "question": "The surface of what is typically 70% water and 10% ice?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c4", "question": "What opera, composed by John Adams, was inspired by Richard Nixon?", "answer": "Nixon in China", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339661", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who sold a monorail to the city of Springfield?", "answer": "Lyle Lanley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c875", "question": "What type of animal are flying foxes?", "answer": "Bats", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59220648a4edfd43a087aded", "question": "Sapphires are typically what color?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b167", "question": "What architect is largely credited with having designed Elizabeth Tower, also known as Big Ben?", "answer": "Augustus Pugin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e7", "question": "Bill Cosby is a famous alumnus of what Philadelphia university?", "answer": "Temple University", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67f", "question": "Who was the first American president to appear on the cover of \"People\" magazine?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015ebcafe83fe1f2a824bfa", "question": "What fall festival activity did the Romans bring to Britain when they invaded?", "answer": "Bobbing for apples", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339994", "question": "What early TV comic was nicknamed \"Mr. Television\"?", "answer": "Milton Berle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adda", "question": "In which war was napalm first used?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e50", "question": "What literary work inspired Jefferson Airplane's \"White Rabbit\" song?", "answer": "Alice in Wonderland", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e93f47ccba3ffe45786cc", "question": "What year was Buddy Holly born?", "answer": "1936", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46d", "question": "Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay were the first people to do what?", "answer": "Reach Mount Everest", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a144", "question": "Who is Scooby Doo's nephew??", "answer": "Scrappy Doo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007822ebd51d85e222ab654", "question": "What title was Henri Matisse's \"Harmony in Red\" originally commissioned under?", "answer": "The painting was originally commissioned in blue. Matisse was dissatisfied with the result and repainted the entire painting red.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590678a9ff9c0647b50a804a", "question": "On what day of the week did January 1, 2016, fall?", "answer": "Friday", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b50b", "question": "What do Las Vegas blackjack dealers stand on?", "answer": "17", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133902a", "question": "Whose Romantic odes include \"Ode to Melancholy\" and \"Ode on a Grecian Urn\"?", "answer": "John Keats", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c4b", "question": "What is the name of Captain Nemo's submarine in \"Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea\"?", "answer": "The Nautilus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b584", "question": "What is the name for Argentinean cowboys?", "answer": "Gauchos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc52", "question": "Who invented Marmite?", "answer": "Justus von Liebig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e988bebfabb9c85d8a96c", "question": "Which leader was renowned for his \"Blood and Iron\" speech?", "answer": "Otto von Bismarck", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339071", "question": "Stephen King's Dark Tower series is about a Gunslinger named what?", "answer": "Roland Deschain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde4e92c6c6b019850c9a85", "question": "What was the name of the anti-Castro group at the \"Bay of Pigs\"?", "answer": "La Brigada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a007", "question": "What city's music scene gave us R.E.M., Danger Mouse, and the B-52s?", "answer": "Athens, Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b627fb6c85e9e634ff47", "question": "Androphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Males, or men", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ae8654e7f28483af1e7fdd0", "question": "What 2015 film broke over 40 box office records upon release?", "answer": "Star Wars: The Force Awakens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918a", "question": "How many keys does a baby grand piano have?", "answer": "88", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd37", "question": "Who scored the famous \"Hand of God\" goal in the 1986 World Cup?", "answer": "Diego Maradona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79c", "question": "What is the name of Neptune's largest moon?", "answer": "Triton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8c", "question": "Who began his career as \"the Cherokee Kid\", the trick roper in Texas Jack's Wild West Circus?", "answer": "Will Rogers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9e02ee748bb36357acdec", "question": "The cities of Xai-Xai, Panda, and Beira are in what country?", "answer": "Mozambique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3c", "question": "What seaport's name is Spanish for \"white house\"?", "answer": "Casablanca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "596761bf2b59efe0e9417ea4", "question": "The 13 stripes on the US Flag represent what?", "answer": "The 13 original colonies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7ce47877e98cb97778a3f", "question": "What are the 3 major islands of the Philippines?", "answer": "Luzon, Visayas and Mindanao", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067b7cff9c0647b50a8064", "question": "What 2009 first-person shooter game mostly takes place in 2016?", "answer": "Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a9", "question": "What does the Latin \"circa\" before a date mean?", "answer": "About", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594a620e2ebb971c1417fb8b", "question": "Which detective was played by Jack Webb in the 1960s TV show \"Dragnet\"?", "answer": "Sergeant Joe Friday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa95e73838c5c8a417f44", "question": "What is Podobromhidrosis?", "answer": "Bad smelling odor from sweat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d24", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Breaking Away\"?", "answer": "Bicycle racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b7", "question": "In what year was the March of Dimes founded?", "answer": "1938", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5922038aa4edfd43a087ade3", "question": "What shapes are used in a Venn diagram?", "answer": "Circles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b61", "question": "A sonnet usually has how many lines?", "answer": "14", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59068002ff9c0647b50a8089", "question": "What motoring show premiered on Amazon Video on November 18, 2016?", "answer": "The Grand Tour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917e", "question": "Who is the voice of Woody in the movie series Toy Story?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c38", "question": "What band performed the theme song from the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b118", "question": "In ancient Japan, all people who gave massages had to be what?", "answer": "Blind", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601601b0fe83fe1f2a824c61", "question": "Many countries do not forthrightly recognize May Day but celebrate which other holiday in its stead?", "answer": "International Workers Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8af6101dd7bf43be5e789", "question": "What do phillumenists collect?", "answer": "Matchboxes and match-related items", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e956e7ccba3ffe45786e0", "question": "Anthocyanins are compounds which produce what?", "answer": "Colors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dec", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"yacht\"?", "answer": "Dutch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc1424469bb8041d07a084", "question": "Introduced in 1993, what was Apple's first tablet computer?", "answer": "Newton MessagePad", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339228", "question": "What is \"Shawshank\" in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A prison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16d", "question": "What's the international radio code word for the letter \"M\"?", "answer": "Mike", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd9", "question": "What year was Mark Wahlberg born?", "answer": "1971", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c83d", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the nephrons?", "answer": "The kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad9de08e748bb36357acde3", "question": "In what country is the grave of the famous German philosopher Immanuel Kant located?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed5", "question": "What stopper, necessary for champagne, did medieval monks invent?", "answer": "The cork", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935b", "question": "Who played the role of Sue Ann Nivens on \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\"?", "answer": "Betty White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff2118231a458464a93c443", "question": "What word describes the act of marking a document in red?", "answer": "Rubrication", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd4", "question": "What Robert Louis Stevenson novel was originally published under the title \"The Sea-Cook\"?", "answer": "Treasure Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7e32ff048f679a45ac09", "question": "Automatonophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Human-like figures", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339913", "question": "What California city was the setting for the TV series \u201cEight is Enough\u201d?", "answer": "Sacramento", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b818", "question": "What did my true love give to me on the fifth day of Christmas?", "answer": "Five golden rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5902a0f0cad1ec93f27df772", "question": "What do you ferment to make kombucha?", "answer": "Sweetened tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39f", "question": "Who is the inventor of the cash register?", "answer": "James Ritty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5902a06fcad1ec93f27df76c", "question": "Which Bohemian city gave us the Pilsner?", "answer": "Pilsen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a72", "question": "Who was the first American artist to have a painting on display in the Louvre?", "answer": "James Whistler", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb72", "question": "What was pictured on the face of the US penny just prior to Abraham Lincoln?", "answer": "Indian head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81e", "question": "What kind of cool star will our Sun become in approximately 5 billion years?", "answer": "A red giant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dcb", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Woozy Winks?", "answer": "Plastic Man", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d7f", "question": "What comedian voiced Mr. Potato Head in the \"Toy Story\" movies?", "answer": "Don Rickles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339326", "question": "In the movie \"Short Circuit\", what is the name of the robot?", "answer": "Johnny Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d2", "question": "What did Harry Houdini die from on Halloween in 1926?", "answer": "Ruptured appendix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f5", "question": "How many episodes of the TV show \"All in the Family\" were made?", "answer": "208", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a354", "question": "What is the only US state that borders a Canadian territory?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80d", "question": "What is the basic flavoring of Kahlua?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd0", "question": "The goddess Athena was responsible for causing whose hair to turn into snakes?", "answer": "Medusa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c90cfc152800b05cac20f0b", "question": "What is the only African nation with Spanish as the official language?", "answer": "Equatorial Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4d", "question": "Who played the male lead in the 2002 movie \"The Hot Chick\"?", "answer": "Rob Schneider", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c181", "question": "The skin of which animal is used to make the finest grade Morocco Leather?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf96", "question": "What is the fear of tapeworms known as?", "answer": "Taeniophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4892ff048f679a45abb0", "question": "How fast can an ostrich run?", "answer": "43 mph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173bec44491cbd7c5a17a1", "question": "Which Roman Emperor made the seven-day week official part of the existing Julian calendar?", "answer": "Constantine the Great", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ce", "question": "Who wrote \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Neil Gaiman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c5b", "question": "What weather phenomenon swept Dorothy Gale to the Land of Oz?", "answer": "A tornado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903a", "question": "Under what pen name did Hector Hugh Munro write?", "answer": "Saki", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133992f", "question": "What was Van Halen\u2019s first, and only #1 hit on the US Billboard singles chart?", "answer": "Jump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8db", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Volta river?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133930f", "question": "In \"The Big Lebowski\", what did Jeffrey Lebowski want replaced after it was urinated on?", "answer": "His rug", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d3f", "question": "In Italian, the Mona Lisa is called what?", "answer": "La Giocondo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a6", "question": "Roadrunners are members of which family of birds?", "answer": "Cuckoos", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600242964be4723ccac22189", "question": "Which novel was first published in October 1847 under the pen name \"Currer Bell\"?", "answer": "\"Jane Eyre\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61f", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Calcium?", "answer": "Ca", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a19", "question": "What UK band had a #1 hit in 1981 with the song \"Don\u2019t You Want Me\"?", "answer": "Human League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c88c", "question": "What does the Binet-Simon scale measure?", "answer": "Intelligence", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a31", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1962 award-winning film \"Lawrence of Arabia\"?", "answer": "Peter O\u2019Toole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b3864fda37788a9a1dc3", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Sparkling Cyanide\"?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a1", "question": "What birds are traditionally used as gas detectors in coal mines?", "answer": "Canaries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f3", "question": "Who discovered the planet Uranus?", "answer": "Sir William Herschel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa8", "question": "Where do fallen Norse warriors go?", "answer": "Valhalla", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ee", "question": "What European country is named for the dark-looking Dinaric Alps?", "answer": "Montenegro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ee", "question": "Beantown is the nickname for what US city?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc34cec223966ae8f887d", "question": "Tiger Woods set or tied 27 records at which 1997 PGA tournament?", "answer": "The Masters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8cc5494b094db9158309e", "question": "What was the name of the protagonist in the 2016 film \u201cZootopia\u201d?", "answer": "Judy Hopps", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4d", "question": "What type of device was the first Sony-branded product, released in 1955?", "answer": "Transistor Radio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00f", "question": "What two metal bands are honored on Beavis and Butt-head's usual t-shirts?", "answer": "AC/DC and Metallica", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938e", "question": "Who played the role of Jim Stark in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1d", "question": "Besides \"Hey Jude\", what other Beatles song title begins with the word \"Hey\"?", "answer": "Hey Bulldog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8fa", "question": "What is an erythrocyte?", "answer": "Red blood cell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8aa6b01dd7bf43be5e75a", "question": "What\u2019s another name for a footrest?", "answer": "Ottoman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a03f", "question": "What is Peter's TV network called on the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "PTV", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2f", "question": "Which two actresses on TV's \"Charlie's Angels\" were meant to be portraying sisters?", "answer": "Farrah Fawcett-Majors and Cheryl Ladd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2d", "question": "Who wrote \"Our Lady of the Flowers\" while in prison?", "answer": "Jean Genet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339378", "question": "Johann Van der Smut is better known as what?", "answer": "Goldmember", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960b", "question": "Who played Captain Leo Davidson in the 2001 version of the movie \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Mark Wahlberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c47a", "question": "In what year was the Toyota Prius hybrid car first commercially sold?", "answer": "1997", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c8", "question": "Which day marks the start of Lent?", "answer": "Ash Wednesday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a41d", "question": "What is the modern day equivalent of Dutch Guiana?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4d97ee08b8581f80b092ac", "question": "Which campaign was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2017 for its work to promote the full implementation of the Treaty on Prohibition of Nuclear Weapons?", "answer": "The International Campaign to Abolish Nuclear Weapons", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523ec4736d4be723796b53", "question": "What three provinces requested a single Dominion be formed in 1867, thus beginning to shape modern Canada?", "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and the Province of Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062a19c9d816e292245c13", "question": "What Flemish Baroque painter is well known for his Counter-Reformation altarpieces?", "answer": "Peter Paul Rubens -- He was a proponent of an extravagant Baroque style that emphasized movement, colour, and sensuality.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb4", "question": "Each Pac-Man maze features 240 regular dots and how many larger \"power pellets\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8e0", "question": "What are the grinding teeth called?", "answer": "Molars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2132b31a458464a93c44e", "question": "The red food-coloring carmine is extracted from which source?", "answer": "Crushed beetles called cochineal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a84", "question": "What 1974 horror film's title weapon was a Poulan 245A?", "answer": "The Texas Chainsaw Massacre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbdc36ce05a3942286ee1", "question": "What was the name of the bar Jerry Lundegaard went to in the film \"Fargo\"?", "answer": "King of Clubs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e6", "question": "The Roadrunner is the official bird of which US state?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d20", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Tin Cup\"?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac59", "question": "What year did the red maple leaf design officially become Canada's flag?", "answer": "1965", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd667cea5bfecdd737e086c", "question": "How many elevators are there in the Empire State Building?", "answer": "73", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0e3affcbed638185eaa24", "question": "A building called \"The Gherkin\" graces which city's skyline?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a4e220565ad31a57c7c3", "question": "What amusement park was home to America\u2019s first roller coaster?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "history"}, {"id": "595241af736d4be723796b63", "question": "What color is human blood that isn't oxygenated?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dad", "question": "Who performs the guest guitar solo on Michael Jackson's \"Beat It\"?", "answer": "Eddie Van Halen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b8c6e662d71a53651027", "question": "How did Herman Melville open the novel \"Moby Dick\"?", "answer": "\"Call me Ishmael.\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb98", "question": "What athletic apparel company took its name from the Greek goddess of Victory?", "answer": "Nike", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c77cf8024f0f7a362efd54e", "question": "In \"The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time\", what are the names of the six races?", "answer": "Hylian, Kokiri, Goron, Zora, Gerudo, Shiekah.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e776b24f84e0b9f9ffb9", "question": "Where is the Pettit National Ice Center located?", "answer": "Milwaukee, Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ba", "question": "Eddie Murphy was the voice of which character in the Shrek movies?", "answer": "Donkey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59524476736d4be723796b69", "question": "What city did Lando Calrissian live in in \"Star Wars V: The Empire Strikes Back\"?", "answer": "Cloud City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ec", "question": "What phenomenon do cereologists study?", "answer": "Crop circles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c829877e98cb977789df", "question": "Which sea lies at one end of the Great Wall of China?", "answer": "The Yellow Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede5326ce05a3942286de8", "question": "Who stars as Hannah Brown in the movie version of Irving Berlin's \"Easter Parade\"", "answer": "Judy Garland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c379", "question": "What name is given to male rhinoceroses?", "answer": "Bulls", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef94406ce05a3942286e95", "question": "Where was the game Chinese Checkers originally produced?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d22abb53d1af65886506", "question": "What year did the first Coca-Cola polar bear ad campaign appear?", "answer": "1922", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecda46ec223966ae8f88e7", "question": "What was the first movie by Pixar to receive a rating higher than G in the United States?", "answer": "The Incredibles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c55d", "question": "What are the four main ingredients of concrete?", "answer": "Sand, water, cement, gravel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a089", "question": "Who plays The Car in the TV show \"Red Dwarf\"?", "answer": "Danny John-Jules", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ee2406d333868d34d774", "question": "What lobster organ is made into a delicacy known as \"tomalley\"?", "answer": "Liver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c1a", "question": "What fictional town is the TV show \"SpongeBob SquarePants\" set in?", "answer": "Bikini Bottom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f43", "question": "Who created the character of Fozzie Bear?", "answer": "Jim Henson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f164946f9b80650dbe7f929", "question": "What is Harry Potter's middle name?", "answer": "James", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339841", "question": "What was the first movie to feature Al Pacino and Robert DeNiro on screen together?", "answer": "Heat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba8", "question": "What 1975 Oscar-winning film features the sadistic Nurse Ratched?", "answer": "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a7", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named for a Scottish village?", "answer": "Strontium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be9b", "question": "In what Olympic sport is the \"clean and jerk\" event held?", "answer": "Weightlifting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb085fbcf631c2414a13b50", "question": "Who sings the \"Friends\" theme song?", "answer": "The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}]